Stay back!
去后面躲着！
The Five Spears have decided to take away your Yokai power.
五矛组织决定夺走你们的妖力
You have no other option but to surrender.
除了投降 你们别无选择
I won't give my kids away.
我绝不会把我的孩子交给别人
Please understand, Hisana.
别执迷不悟 久那
Humans and Yokai cannot coexist.
人类与妖怪是无法共存的
Izuna!
伊豆！
Mother!
妈妈！
Izuna.
伊豆
No!
不！
Thanks for your patience, everyone.
谢谢大家的耐心等待
Without further ado, the long-awaited pinnacle battle of eSports players,
话不多说 万众期待已久的 电竞选手巅峰之战
E LEGENDS will now begin!
“电竞传奇”现在正式开始！
E LEGENDS!
电竞传奇！
What the hell are they doing? Damn it!
他们在搞什么啊？见鬼！
This event today is the culmination of my life!
我的人生成败全取决于今天的比赛！
Your life was ruined by becoming a jobless graduate.
你变成了找不到工作的毕业生 你的人生已经被毁了
It's not over yet! I mean, it hasn't even begun!
还没结束呢！比赛甚至还没开始呢！
Well, I'm here. I'll be with you next year and the year after.
不管怎样 我一直在 明年和后年我都会陪在你身边
Hey.
喂
Is Princess Izuna-imiki a wonderful Yokai?
伊豆之内干姬公主 是一只出色的妖怪吗？
Yes.
她是
Noble, dignified and an unparalleled beauty!
高贵、端庄 以及一副无与伦比的美丽容颜！
That can't be denied. She's incredibly cool.
这无可否认 她确实非常酷
Hey, guys.
喂 各位
Consider Arisa's feelings. She's being targeted by Izzy.
拜托你们顾虑一下亚里沙的感受 伊姬马上就要来杀她了
So, focus!
大家专心点！
Even the living deads are Hikarists?
就连活死人都变成光迷了？
Listen up, everyone.
大家听好了
That Yokai will come after her final target, Arisa.
那只妖怪马上就要来 解决她的最终目标 亚里沙了
Don't let her escape, no matter what.
无论发生什么 千万别让她逃了
Did you get in touch with Tadashi?
你联系到忠士了吗？
No.
没有
Is he really involved in this incident?
他真的和这桩命案有关吗？
Don't worry. Our son would never harm anyone.
别担心 我们的儿子绝不会伤害别人的
But given the circumstances, it's hard to deny his involvement.
但鉴于现在的情况 他很难和这案子撇清关系
He must have a reason.
他一定有自己的理由
Is he safe?
他不会有危险吧？
I'll bring him back for sure. Don't worry.
我一定会把他带过来的 你别担心
I'll call you back.
我回头再打给你
RENJO LAW OFFICE
连城律师事务所
Show me Arisa's whereabouts.
告诉我亚里沙在哪儿
What's going on?
你这是干什么？
Where's my son?
我儿子在哪儿？
What is this about?
你问我这个做什么？
Answer my question!
回答我的问题！
The monk at Nijoji Temple, where you frequently visit,
你经常去拜访的那个二浄寺的和尚
was found dead, just like the son of the Ippongi Construction.
和一本木建设的继承人一样死于非命
And the missing interns, too.
那个失踪的实习生也是
They're all connected to you.
他们都和你有关系
Stop making false accusations.
请不要对我进行不实指控
No, Captain! This goes beyond rule violations!
别这样 队长！ 这已经不仅仅是违规了！
Captain!
队长！
Don't you think you can escape.
别以为你可以逍遥法外
Did you do it?
你弄好了吗？
Of course!
当然了！
With this, we can track down Sakon.
有了这个 我们就能追踪左近的行踪了
Hopefully, we'll find Tadashi, too.
希望我们也能借此找到忠士
I hope so.
希望如此
Cool!
太酷了吧！
What a perfect setup!
这些戏服也太逼真了！
Awesome!
了不起！
Now, onto the next stage.
接下来 进入下个赛程
All of you, get out of here if you don't want to die.
所有人 如果不想死的话 就赶紧离开这里
Otherwise...
否则…
I'll kill you all!
我就把你们全杀了！
Hachi!
八公！
What are they doing?
他们在做什么呢？
Beni!
贝尼！
Terauchi!
寺内！
It stinks!
好臭啊！
Distribute these to everyone.
把这些分发给大家
I'll be the bait to lure out Izzy.
我会充当引伊姬过来的诱饵
First, we'll sever Hachi and Izzy's bond with a spell.
首先 我们要用咒语 切断八公和伊姬之间的连结
Then, the binding spell to expel her from this world.
然后用束缚咒将她驱逐出这个世界
Here she comes.
她来了
Izzy.
伊姬
Princess Izuna!
伊豆公主！
So, it was you.
原来是你
Move, Hachi. Her head can end all of this.
让开 八公 她的头颅可以为这一切划上句号
I'll put an end to everything.
我会终结这一切
You're the one who will be banished.
被驱逐的只会是你
Izzy.
伊姬
Izuna!
伊豆！
You are calamity itself.
你就是个灾星
Now!
就是现在！
Circle of Five.
五人成阵
A magic circle...
法阵…
Within the magic circle, your power is null.
在这个法阵里 你无法施展出妖力
Arisa, the binding spell!
亚里沙 用束缚咒！
Stop!
别念了！
We have to chant the spell!
你干什么？我们必须得念咒！
Arisa!
亚里沙！
Are you all right?
你还好吗？
The time has come to bury you completely.
时机已成熟 这次我会将你彻底埋葬
Stop!
住手！
Hachi!
八公！
Princess Izuna!
伊豆公主！
All of you are miserable.
你们都是一群悲哀之人
Losers who can't even protect their own lives.
一群连自己的命都保不住的废物
Get them.
开始攻击
Kill them all, except for the Guardians of the Five Spears.
除了五矛的守护者外 将所有人尽数杀光
Seriously?
开什么玩笑？
Wait, aren't we allies?
等等 我们不是战友吗？
Allies?
战友？
Don't make me laugh.
别逗我了
You're finished.
你的死局已定
Princess Izuna!
伊豆公主！
What a fool.
真是个蠢货
This ends with you.
这一切将由你结束
Izzy!
伊姬！
Why...
为什么...
The magatama is reacting to you.
勾玉对你有反应
Hachi...
八公…
You...
你…
I've been curious since I heard about
自从我听到五矛的仪式后
the Five Spears' ritual.
我就觉得有点不对劲
Fifteen years ago, Saori Goromaru, the head of the Five Spears,
15年前 五矛组织的头领 五郎丸纱织
secretly performed a ritual,
悄悄举行仪式
giving an amulet to a young child to bestow them with its power.
将一枚护身符赠予一名幼童 赐予他们力量
Do you remember?
你还记得吗？
The spring I took you to?
我带你去的那处泉水
Why was it that place?
当时我为什么会带你去那儿？
Seeing this, I remembered everything.
看到这个 我全都想起来了
Now, if you drink this,
来 喝下这个
you'll be set to embrace your destiny.
你就做好迎接自己命运的准备了
Tadashi.
忠士
My precious grandson.
我的宝贝孙子
You're...
你是…
I'm...
我是…
...the Guardian.
…守护者
I am your final
我是你最后一个
target.
目标
Stay away!
别过来！
Izzy.
伊姬
If you choose to liberate your family and friends,
如果你选择放你的家人和朋友自由
I would gladly offer my life.
那么我愿意献出我的生命
In return,
我唯一的条件是
could you make just one promise?
你能答应我一件事吗？
Let me be the last one
让我成为你伤害的
you hurt.
最后一人
I...
我…
...don't want to see anyone else get hurt.
…不想再看到其他人受伤害了
Izzy!
伊姬！
Return to your world!
回你的世界去！
Hachi.
八公
I'm sorry.
对不起
-Uncle? -I see.
-叔叔？ -原来如此
I get it now.
现在我终于懂了
What a masterpiece.
命运真是奇妙
I never expected a Guardian to be summoning Yokai.
我从没想到 召唤妖怪的竟然会是一名守护者
Arisa.
亚里沙
Forgive me.
原谅我
Once you're gone,
待你死后
all the power of the Five Spears will be mine!
五矛的所有力量都会归我所有！
Advance!
上！
Suspect arrested!
嫌犯已被逮捕！
Dad...
老爸…
Tadashi.
忠士
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Yeah.
嗯
You're all right now, son.
现在你安全了 儿子
ONE MONTH LATER
一个月后
The case of the mysterious serial murders that shocked the nation.
迷雾重重的连环杀人案 让全国为之震惊
Captain Inukai, who handled the case, is here to give us details.
负责调查此案的犬饲队长 将为我们解答案件细节
There was an accomplice to Sakon Renjo.
连城左近有一个共犯
We're still investigating their relationship and the motive
我们仍在调查他们的关系 以及这几起凶案
behind these events.
背后的动机
An unidentified group
案发现场曾出现过
suspected to be accomplices was spotted at the crime scene,
一个疑似为嫌疑人共犯的不明团体
and we are currently locating them.
目前我们正在寻找这些人
Dad, you're famous!
老爸 你出名了！
Turn that off.
把电视关了
Fine.
好
My friend wanted your autograph, Dad.
我的朋友想要你的签名 老爸
I'm leaving.
我要出发了
Tadashi, have a seat. Let's eat together.
忠士 进来坐 我们一起吃饭
But there's no time...
可是我来不及了…
Here.
给
An omelet.
是煎蛋卷
-Okay. -Good.
-好吧 -这才乖
-Thanks for the meal. -Go ahead.
-谢谢您做的饭 -快吃吧
Tadashi.
忠士
Don't forget your therapy appointment today.
别忘了你今天得去做心理咨询
I know.
我知道
It's good.
很好吃
I've got to go to class now.
我得去上课了
I'm going, too.
我也得走了
Have a nice day.
祝你们度过愉快的一天
-Have a nice day. -Thanks.
-祝你们度过愉快的一天 -谢谢
-See you.
-再见 -拜拜
They're good kids.
他们俩都是好孩子
Yeah.
是啊
No matter what happens, I don't want to lose them.
无论如何 我都不想失去他们
Yeah, it's okay now.
是啊 一切都过去了
The case is solved.
案子已经破了
No.
不
There's something I haven't told you yet.
有件事我一直没告诉你
Get in.
进去吧
I'm sorry.
十分抱歉
Sakon.
左近
How did that Yokai
一开始 那只妖怪
come into this world in the first place?
是怎么来到这个世界的
The forbidden book.
因为那本禁书
It seems a foolish intern stole it.
似乎是一位愚蠢的实习生把书盗走了
The chaos began with that.
这才引发了一系列的混乱
Do you think I didn't notice
你以为我没注意到
you were trying to steal
你试图从我们手中
the forbidden spells from us?
偷走禁忌咒语吗？
The release of the forbidden spells
让禁忌咒语流传出去
was definitely not my intention.
绝不是我的本意
If that idiot hadn't posted on the Internet...
如果不是那个白痴 把东西发到了网上…
I'm grateful to you.
其实我很感谢你
Thanks to your failure,
多亏你失败了
things have progressed quite smoothly.
事情才得以顺利进行
We were able to eliminate the weak from the Five Spears
我们借此机会清除了 五矛组织中的无能者
and evolve.
进化到了新高度
Once I leave this place,
待我离开这里
you won't remember anything.
你便会忘记一切
I heard they no longer offer ancient folklore studies.
我听说学校 以后不开古代民间传说课了
Officially, because there's no replacement for Professor Sawada.
官方的说辞是 因为他们找不到人接替泽田教授
I would've gotten good grades in that class.
如果那门课没取消 我一定能拿个好成绩
But we know magic now. Why attend the lectures?
但现在我们都知道魔法了 还上课做什么？
I have to go. I have a counseling session.
我得走了 还要去做心理咨询呢
I need to discuss as they expect.
我得按照他们的要求 去聊聊那些事
Hey.
嘿
Have you talked to your dad about the possibility
你有没有和你爸说
of your grandmother being involved?
你的姥姥可能与这事有关？
Not yet.
还没有
There must be a reason, so we need to find that first.
发生这些事一定是有原因的 我们得自己先弄清楚
I see.
懂了
So, no updates from her?
对了 你最近有她的消息吗？
I guess the final ritual went well, then.
看来最后的仪式顺利完成了
It still feels weird, you know.
但我还是感觉怪怪的
Like...
就像是…
I don't sense Izzy,
我无法感知到伊姬
so our bond must have been severed for sure,
所以我们的连结肯定已经被切断了
but there's this lingering discomfort.
但是我心头总有一种挥之不去的难受
She was quite interesting.
她是个很有趣的人
I can't quite put it into words, but we have to move forward.
我不知道该说什么 但我们必须要翻篇了
Right.
是啊
-Well, I'm off! -Yup.
-那我走喽！ -去吧
Arisa.
亚里沙
If you're watching this,
当你看到这段视频时
I might not be in this world anymore.
我可能已经不在人世了
There's something about
关于连城家族的命运
the Renjo family's destiny that I need to tell you.
我还有事要告诉你
It's about your parents.
是你父母的事
Your parents weren't killed by Yokai.
你的父母并非死于妖怪之手
Your parents were killed by...
杀害你父母的其实是…
I still sense the aura of Yokai in this world.
我能感觉到 那股妖气依然在这个世界里
A bond that can't be completely severed even with spells.
一段即使用咒语 也难以彻底切断的连结
It's intriguing
很有意思
and troublesome.
但也十分棘手
We must definitely expel that Yokai.
我们必须将那妖怪彻底驱逐
She's not suitable for my grandson.
她配不上我的孙子
Tadashi is no ordinary Guardian.
忠士可不是普通的守护者
That child possesses special powers.
那孩子身负特别之力
You've reached a Yokai from a place beyond human knowledge.
我是来自超凡脱俗之地的妖怪
Leave a message.
有事请留言
Izzy, it's me.
伊姬 是我
I don't know if you can hear this message
我不知道你能不能收到这段留言
or if you're still in our world.
也不知道你是否还在我们的世界
There's something I want to say.
我有话想跟你说
I think I've made a lot of mistakes.
我觉得自己犯了很多错
I did many things without thinking of the consequences.
很多事我没有考虑后果 便去鲁莽地做了
I was always nervous, lacked confidence in everything,
从前我总是容易紧张 对所有事都缺乏自信
and would easily run away.
遇事总是逃避
But now,
但现在
I don't want to give up.
我不想放弃
Meeting you
与你的相遇
made me feel like I want to choose my own path
让我觉得我想选择自己要走的路
and make my way through.
并且要把我选的路走到底
Fate isn't something imposed on you by someone else.
命运并不是其他人强加于你的
You choose your own path.
人要选择自己的路
Hey, Izzy. No matter where you are,
嘿 伊姬 无论你在哪儿
I'm going to find you.
我一定会找到你